Dear Hiring Manager,

I am a software engineer with a background in product/program management and customer-facing roles in SaaS companies. I've worked with clients, engineering teams, operations along with other stakeholders. I believe my capability as a developer, my client-focused attitude, punctuated by my expertise in collaborative problem solving makes me an ideal candidate for the support engineer position.

- I am people orientated. As a SaaS sales and implementation manager, I effectively bridged the ports between customer requirements and engineering. I had to gather insights from both perspectives to optimize the flow and integrity of critical information.
 My natural inclination to bring groups together also translates into what I enjoy the most technically, I love exploring APIs and bridging systems together.
- I'm a technical proficient software developer. I recently completed a <u>full-stack project</u> using Ruby on Rails with React and Redux to replicate the key features of Tumblr. I am also experienced with JavaScript which I have demonstrated by building a simple HTML5 canvas click and point <u>2D action game</u>.
- I'm a meticulous planner and deadline-driven. This is highlighted in my <u>MERN stack</u> team project called Ride, a motorcycle trip tracking and sharing app developed by 4 engineers within a deadline of 7 days. I built a structured yet adaptive timeline, we've made sure each one of us had tangible goals and objectives for each day.

I excel at quickly learning new technology and immediately applying them to my personal and professional projects. I enjoy helping others understand concepts and techniques that I have previously learned. I thrive in collaborative environments and actively seek opportunities to contribute. As a people advocating technologist, I am certain I can be a great addition to your team.

Thank you for your consideration!

Miles Song



916-430-7021 miles.song.ca@gmail.com Portfolio LinkedIn Github AnaelList

SKILLS

JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, SQL, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, jQuery, AWS, Python, GraphQL

PROJECTS

Skyscraper | React/Redux | Ruby on Rails | Postgresql | AWS | HTML | CSS

live | github

Tumblr-inspired single page app that allows users to upload media

- Designed API endpoints and SQL database schema using active record ORM.
- Incorporated Redux selector patterns to architect highly scalable and uni-directional front-end state management.
- Leveraged AWS S3 for receipt image storage and utilized file compression to reduce latency and storage cost.
- Integrated Webpack and Babel to ensure a reliable uniform user experience across web browsers.

Ride | React | Node | MongoDB | Express | Mapbox | HTML | CSS

live | github

Motorcycle trips review app for users to plan and share rides

- Implemented User Auth by encrypting user details via the JSON Webtoken library to be sent over HTTP using **Axios** to be decrypted via the **JWT-Decode** library on the frontend.
- Utilized Mongoose ORM to map results of database queries onto JavaScript objects to be manipulated and returned to frontend, separating concerns and following **MVC** best practices.
- Designed **CSS transitions** on ride show / create, enhancing the user experience with smooth transitions.

Cheddar Cheesel Javascript | HTML Canvas | Webpack

live | github

Colorful point and click action survival game

- Designed game logic and browser render with **object oriented programming** in Javascript.
- Implemented custom movement, gravity, and object collision functions to provide a physics engine that allows objects in the game to intuitively interact with each other.
- Authored algorithms to generate game entities pseudo-randomly from a set of defined patterns, in order to strike a balance between predictability and freshness each playthrough.

EXPERIENCE

Program Manager

App Academy 03/2019 - 08/2019

- Managed the Engineering Interview Prep product, a program dedicated to honing technical abilities of mid-career software engineers.
- Implementing and managing changes and interventions to ensure project goals are achieved.
- Developing an evaluation method to assess program strengths and identify areas for improvement.

Product Implementation Manager

CLOUDCC- CRM 02/2018 - 02/2019

- Assisting in requirement gathering and API design for client customized SaaS solutions
- Facilitate post-sales and technical integration between the engineering team and clients.

Technology Consultant

Delphi Education Technology Consulting

08/2015 - 02/2018

- Providing consultation and implementation service for secondary and post-secondary institutions seeking technology solutions.
- Maintain and develop accounts and provide individual clients and institutions.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology -AppAcademy -

B.S. Economics, 2011

Full-stack web development 2019